<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Christianity प्रेतमतम् on hindu-vichArAH हिन्दु-विचाराः</title>
    <link>https://hindutva.github.io/main/rivals/abe-disease/zombie-cult/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Christianity प्रेतमतम् on hindu-vichArAH हिन्दु-विचाराः</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://hindutva.github.io/main/rivals/abe-disease/zombie-cult/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Anti-science</title>
      <link>https://hindutva.github.io/main/rivals/abe-disease/zombie-cult/anti-science/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hindutva.github.io/main/rivals/abe-disease/zombie-cult/anti-science/</guid>
      <description>Problems with Science  Medieval History  The renaissance spirit owes a lot to the pagan revivalist Plethon, whose school was unfortunately subverted. In the Middle Ages, the view that the Book of Nature and the Book of Scripture must be harmonious (because they have the same &amp;ldquo;author&amp;rdquo;) led to non-literal interpretations of scripture to conform to empirical data. [??]  William of Conch (1100-1154) said: &amp;ldquo;Since the same earth, water and heat continue to exist today, there is no natural reason why new human races are not produced naturally from their interaction.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jesus</title>
      <link>https://hindutva.github.io/main/rivals/abe-disease/zombie-cult/jesus/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hindutva.github.io/main/rivals/abe-disease/zombie-cult/jesus/</guid>
      <description>Personality  Below, we talk about the Nicene Jesus. (Gnostic Christ seems have been *much* better. There were other &amp;ldquo;Christ&amp;quot;s too - some say all of them were fictional.) Jesus, if he existed, was racist. (As more non-jew converts came in, this was subsumed by a broader out-group hostility.)  (Matthew 15:21-28 and Mark 7:24-30) - &amp;ldquo;Gentile (non-Jew) woman once begged him to cast away the demon that had possessed her daughter&amp;hellip; He cold-heartedly told the woman that only the Jews were his children and that the Gentiles were dogs.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>