<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;स्वरक्षणम् (Defence) on hindu-vichArAH हिन्दु-विचाराः</title>
    <link>https://hindutva.github.io/main/polity/external-affairs/defence/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;स्वरक्षणम् (Defence) on hindu-vichArAH हिन्दु-विचाराः</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://hindutva.github.io/main/polity/external-affairs/defence/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Adaption - technology and tactics</title>
      <link>https://hindutva.github.io/main/polity/external-affairs/defence/Adaption_-_technology_and_tactics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hindutva.github.io/main/polity/external-affairs/defence/Adaption_-_technology_and_tactics/</guid>
      <description>Horse Range  Range depended on breed, the weight of the rider (and armor), and many other factors, such as environmental conditions. Mongol ponies, for instance, were bred for stamina - i.e., traveling long hours and distances at a steady pace. The scrappy little Indian-bred horses used by the far-ranging Maratha cavalry in India were similarly bred for long-haul stamina. Infantry could cover at most 30 km per day. Mongols often used multiple (3/4) horses per rider, and stored meat between saddle and the horse to each on horseback.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bhima Koregaon myth</title>
      <link>https://hindutva.github.io/main/polity/external-affairs/defence/bhIma-koregaon-myth/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hindutva.github.io/main/polity/external-affairs/defence/bhIma-koregaon-myth/</guid>
      <description>Intro  &amp;ldquo;the last battle of the Anglo-Maratha war was fought at Koregaon village on the banks of Bhima river near Pune. The battle marked the firm hold of the British Empire in India. The British erected an obelisk at the battle ground in the memory of the dead. It has 49 names, 22 of them are identified by their ‘nak’ suffix as Mahars.&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;It was&amp;hellip; used by the first batch of Mahar leaders such as Gopal Baba Walangkar, Shivram Janba Kamble and even Ramji Ambedkar, B.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cases</title>
      <link>https://hindutva.github.io/main/polity/external-affairs/defence/cases/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hindutva.github.io/main/polity/external-affairs/defence/cases/</guid>
      <description>High level vids: YT1. Defence of oDDiyAna (swat) - MT.  Arab intrusion into sindh It started with a naval raid sent by kaliif umar companion of muhammad, which was destroyed by chAlukya-s near thAne [MT].
&amp;ldquo;It was only after 13 successive attempts that the Moslems finally breached and destroyed the Hindu kingdom of sindhu. .. But one major unanswered question of history arises: what was the cause of failure of the saindhava kingdom against ibn Qasim when it had until then pretty effectively resisted the Moslems for a period of nearly 75 years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Division of power, scale-free feudalism</title>
      <link>https://hindutva.github.io/main/polity/external-affairs/defence/Division_of_power_scale-free_feudalism/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hindutva.github.io/main/polity/external-affairs/defence/Division_of_power_scale-free_feudalism/</guid>
      <description>Consider the list of individual heroes involved in politics and war. Thence we learn the following. Where ever kShatriyas tasked with protecting their land (as if it were their wife) and subjects (as if they were their children) fell, others rose to take their place (eg: harihara and bukka, chandragupta maurya, shivAji, reDDi chieftains). They were guided and inspired by learned men and sages (eg: tukArAm, vidyAraNya, chANakya). Further, their efforts were financed often by taxation, but also sometimes by donations from merchants.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Maratha loss</title>
      <link>https://hindutva.github.io/main/polity/external-affairs/defence/marATha-loss/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hindutva.github.io/main/polity/external-affairs/defence/marATha-loss/</guid>
      <description>Discussions -  MT11, MT04 WP.    Reasons  British grand strategy and understanding of the enemy was much superior to ours.  &amp;ldquo;The British had been planning on how to colonize India as far back as early 1700&amp;rsquo;s while the Marathas were in their life and death struggle with the Mughals.&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;Besides, the British Plan already had the solid backing of a very thorough study of India by now and evaluation of its people.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Misplaced mercy and lack of ruthlessness</title>
      <link>https://hindutva.github.io/main/polity/external-affairs/defence/Misplaced_mercy_and_lack_of_ruthlessness/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hindutva.github.io/main/polity/external-affairs/defence/Misplaced_mercy_and_lack_of_ruthlessness/</guid>
      <description>One drawback we hindus had was misplaced generosity - a paucity of ruthlessness. The source is nothing but moral weakness and fragility. These people want approval and admiration of others. This is the disease that motivated moronic actions right from dharmarAja to PrithvirAja Chauhan to Nehru and Gandhi.
 Think what kind of disaster it would have been if kRShNa thought that way. That yudhiShThira gave duryodhana his choice of weapon and combatant when he emerged from the lake hiding spot, and kRShNa scolded him - &amp;ldquo;Again, even now you are gambling!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Myths</title>
      <link>https://hindutva.github.io/main/polity/external-affairs/defence/myths/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hindutva.github.io/main/polity/external-affairs/defence/myths/</guid>
      <description>In recent times, many have succumbed to the British manipulative theories such as (MT&amp;rsquo;s analysis here):
 generally effeminate nature of Hindus (relative to vigorous Muhammadan-s and Europeans) superiority of European military discipline  Firing by rank  MT: &amp;ldquo;This culture of using the long-bow had already inculcated in the Hindus the precursor to the principle of fire by ranks – indeed Indian texts have long described the constant showers of arrows maintained by different kinds of archers in large scale combats.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resistance to alien invasions and resurgence</title>
      <link>https://hindutva.github.io/main/polity/external-affairs/defence/Resistance_to_alien_invasions_and_resurgence/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hindutva.github.io/main/polity/external-affairs/defence/Resistance_to_alien_invasions_and_resurgence/</guid>
      <description>Constant low level pesant revolt against muslim rulers was noted by Peter Mundy, Manucci, Abul Fazl, Bernier, Jahangir, Kopf. (sItA-rAm-goel&amp;rsquo;s assessment here. )  (Dis)Unity Effective disunited resistance Very strong resistance to foreign invasion has been repeatedly observed. With regard to the Muslim invasions, it must be noted that for over a 1000 years, there was on average 1 battle every month between local resistors and Islamic armies. Even as proud civilizations from Iran to Indonesia fell, the native Hindu culture survived.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>