<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Problems on hindu-vichArAH हिन्दु-विचाराः</title>
    <link>https://hindutva.github.io/polity/sick-india/problems/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Problems on hindu-vichArAH हिन्दु-विचाराः</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://hindutva.github.io/polity/sick-india/problems/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Dumbocracy</title>
      <link>https://hindutva.github.io/polity/sick-india/problems/dumbocracy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hindutva.github.io/polity/sick-india/problems/dumbocracy/</guid>
      <description>Here we examine problems of democracy and briefly consider alternative systems of government
Problems  The &amp;ldquo;one person one vote&amp;rdquo; paradigm prominent in democracies rests on an unnatural, false assumption: That all men are equal in their abilities and judgement. Politicians compete for attention and approval of masses (who in heterogeneous countries like India tend to be bottom heavy - ie dominated by incompetents). So, their legislative goals and administration becomes flawed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>kAshmIra</title>
      <link>https://hindutva.github.io/polity/sick-india/problems/kashmir/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hindutva.github.io/polity/sick-india/problems/kashmir/</guid>
      <description>Events  &amp;ldquo;By 1989, with Rajiv Gandhi blundering on several fronts, VP Singh formed a Government. Immediately, Kashmir exploded: The drama of Union Home Minister Mufti Sayeed’s daughter’s kidnapping forced India to free terrorists. A murderous exodus of Kashmiri Hindus followed &amp;mdash; the seventh in a series of genocidal rounds of ethnic cleansing since 1389.&amp;rdquo;  Short term desiderata Article 370 should stay repealed, that kAshmIri paNDits and any hindu-s willing to live there be resettled in kAshmIr with dignity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sick fracture</title>
      <link>https://hindutva.github.io/polity/sick-india/problems/sikh_fracture/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hindutva.github.io/polity/sick-india/problems/sikh_fracture/</guid>
      <description>Events  &amp;ldquo;Nehru’s betrayal of Partition-era promises to Sikhs regarding “a territorial area within the nation to develop its own life and culture (…) with a great deal of autonomy for its constituent units.” (October 1945; reiterated in July 1946). Sikhs had lost a great deal and felt a need to culturally consolidate within India.&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;Operation Blue Star was not the first time the Golden Temple Complex was assaulted post-Independence. In 1955, protesters gathered there demanding a Punjabi-language State were assaulted by the police.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Subversion</title>
      <link>https://hindutva.github.io/polity/sick-india/problems/subversion/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hindutva.github.io/polity/sick-india/problems/subversion/</guid>
      <description>Summary  A strong self determined India is the natural result of Hindutva coming to power. Naturally, several foreign powers do not like this. Subversion of hinduism by foreign and domestic forces is considered in the hinduism subversion page. Media connection - see here.  Pyschological operations intro Psy-ops is real, and has been used very effectively in the past. The strength of India&amp;rsquo;s domestic fools are a direct result of old soviet subversion.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
