<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;History on hindu-vichArAH हिन्दु-विचाराः</title>
    <link>https://hindutva.github.io/main/history/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;History on hindu-vichArAH हिन्दु-विचाराः</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://hindutva.github.io/main/history/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Administrative</title>
      <link>https://hindutva.github.io/main/history/administration/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hindutva.github.io/main/history/administration/</guid>
      <description>Civil administration  Politicians who gained standing in military.  Roman consuls with annual appointments in the first punic war.   Separation of military and civil services leadership.  Consolidation of the Roman empire [YT]   Law enforcement  Pune under marATha-s TW17.    Succession  Hereditary Adaption  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Event record</title>
      <link>https://hindutva.github.io/main/history/event_record/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hindutva.github.io/main/history/event_record/</guid>
      <description>Record  Meta  For date conversion tools, see this page. For conventions used by maraTha historians, see maraTha page.  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fiji</title>
      <link>https://hindutva.github.io/main/history/fiji/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hindutva.github.io/main/history/fiji/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;In Fiji H mistake was family planning + not joining army during ww2, at 1 pt it was 51% Indian. Indians had a higher TFR. During ww2 Brits opened up army but these idiots demanded equal pay where as natives joined up &amp;amp; gained full ctrl of army. Also Indian TFR fell below Fijian &amp;quot; -SP17 &amp;quot; &amp;ldquo;Prior to World War II, soldiers served voluntarily and were paid &amp;ldquo;capitation grants&amp;rdquo; according to efficiency ratings without regard to race.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Indonesia</title>
      <link>https://hindutva.github.io/main/history/indonesia/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hindutva.github.io/main/history/indonesia/</guid>
      <description>Bali  Bali population is dropping. Daily school practice trisandhya - IMG.  Chinese role  Anti chinese riots in may 1998, involving looting, burning, temple desecration, gang rapes, murders - WI, YT; resulting in many Chinese fleeing the country, and some converting to Islam.  Current Anti-hindu situation  Indonesian Hindus faced &amp;ldquo;increasing discrimination&amp;rdquo; from a rapidly Islamizing Indonesian Muslim society, including from members of &amp;ldquo;so-called moderate groups Muhammadiyah and Nahdlatul Ulama,&amp;rdquo; as well as from the government.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Malaysia</title>
      <link>https://hindutva.github.io/main/history/malaysia/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hindutva.github.io/main/history/malaysia/</guid>
      <description>Islamification via bhumiputera laws  At independence the non Mohammedan pop was nearly half, now drastically reduced thru bhumiputra laws favoring indolent mohammedans. If a Malay leaves Islam, he is stripped of all his &amp;ldquo;Bumiputera&amp;rdquo; rights.  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Military (General)</title>
      <link>https://hindutva.github.io/main/history/military/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hindutva.github.io/main/history/military/</guid>
      <description>Hindu military history and evaluation - see here.
Significant alien wars  Carthage vs Rome  First punic war [YT]  Consistent glory-hungry aggressiveness on the Roman side. Brilliant naval innovations.   Battle of cannae [YT]  Great flanking and feinting.     Fortifications  Constantinople - Theodosian walls [YT]. Not overcome for over 1k years.    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Phillipines</title>
      <link>https://hindutva.github.io/main/history/phillipines/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hindutva.github.io/main/history/phillipines/</guid>
      <description>Hindu past Kingdoms Prior to its Christianization and Islamization, Philippines used to have quite many Indianized kingdoms. PB
These included
-Tondo -Butuan -Cebu -Madyas
&amp;ldquo;The Rajahante of Cebu was interesting because it was found by Sri Lumay who claimed Chola descent. When the Cholas invaded Sriwijaya, a branch of Cholas settled there are married native Malay wives. One of the princes went to Philippines to establish his own kingdom.&amp;rdquo;
Culture Some places in Philippines still have names of Sanskrit etymology (eg: visaya-s, manila); local language - esp religious language borrows from deva dharma.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>rAjput muslim alliance</title>
      <link>https://hindutva.github.io/main/history/rAjput-muslim-alliance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hindutva.github.io/main/history/rAjput-muslim-alliance/</guid>
      <description>Hindu service during late Mogol days  &amp;ldquo;The rAjpUt-s, though diminished in their national sense since the days of the great struggle of mahArANa pratAp and his son amar singh, were still not devoid of their Hindu affinities&amp;hellip; Their position was not unlike that of most common Hindus of today – they may work faithfully for the enemy, despite having their sub-current Hindu sympathies still intact. &amp;quot; MT &amp;ldquo;There were still pockets of brave rAjpUt resistance that was no less in fury than that of the mahArATTa-s&amp;hellip; There were also great uprisings of the bundela-s Chatrasal, prahAr singh and devI singh and another rAjpUt bhagavant singh against the Moslems in this period.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sindh betrayal</title>
      <link>https://hindutva.github.io/main/history/sindh_betrayal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hindutva.github.io/main/history/sindh_betrayal/</guid>
      <description>Reference: McLean thesis here.  Difference in early collaboration  &amp;ldquo;There are clear discrepancies between the Buddhists and the Hindus of Sind both in their immediate response to the Arab invasion .and in the long term effect which the occupation had on them. That is, Buddhists tended to collaborate to a significantly greater extent and at an earlier date than did Hindus and, more&amp;rsquo; importantly, Buddhism disappeared completely as a viable religious system during the Arab period while Hinduism has continued to survive, in varying conditions of prosperity, until the present day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tarim basin</title>
      <link>https://hindutva.github.io/main/history/tarim_basin/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hindutva.github.io/main/history/tarim_basin/</guid>
      <description> See here.  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>स्थानानि Places</title>
      <link>https://hindutva.github.io/main/history/places/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hindutva.github.io/main/history/places/</guid>
      <description>punjAb  500 BCE - IMG.   afghAnistAn  500 BCE - IMG.    BengaLUru sambhoji चिक्कबळ्ळापुरे नन्दिपर्वते शासनम्॥
श्रीनन्दीश्वराय नमः।
देशे कर्णाटके पूर्वे पर्वतो नन्दिनामकः।
अत्युन्नतो ऽभेद्यश् च मार्गेनैकेन संयुतः॥
चम्पकाश्वत्थनारङ्ग-तमालैः परितः श्रितः।
अत्युच्छ्रयो महावप्रो देवालयविभूषितः॥
राज्ये बळ्ळापुरस्यैव दुर्गं कृत्वा महागिरिम्।
मेने शत्रुभयात् त्रातुं स्वयम् अस्ति विनिश्चितम्॥
गृहीतुं दुर्गम् अग्राह्यं म्लेच्छो बहुबलान्वितः।
आजगाम, ततो जातस् ताडतोऽत्यन्त-विह्वलः॥
शकाब्द-सहस्रं द्वि-त्रि-शत-द्वे-वर्षे रौद्रौ श्रावण-शुद्ध-षष्ठ्यां बुधे च वारे शिव-च्छत्रपतेः कुमारः शम्भोजिराड् अत्र मुदानुशास्ति।</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>