<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;News rags on hindu-vichArAH हिन्दु-विचाराः</title>
    <link>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/rags/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;News rags on hindu-vichArAH हिन्दु-विचाराः</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/rags/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Brahmin in WSJ 2020</title>
      <link>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/rags/brAhmin_wsj_oped/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/rags/brAhmin_wsj_oped/</guid>
      <description>Reaction to WSJ anti-brahmin op-ed  I write today on behalf of the Hindu community to express our outrage regarding WSJ’s Op-Ed,titled “Canceling Student Debt Will Be a Brahmin Bailout” (Nov. 29th, 2020) by Mr. Zaid Jilani. It is a telling sign of our times that an Op-Ed lacking erudition and factual accuracy while reinforcing Hinduphobia and stereotypes of Hindus, is part of a newspaper such as the WSJ. The callous usage of the word “Brahmin” amounts to blatant propaganda and a thinly veiled attack on the Hindu community and will promote hatred and animosity towards Hindus in the United States and worldwide.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Opindia Fake news</title>
      <link>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/rags/opindia_fake_news_examples/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/rags/opindia_fake_news_examples/</guid>
      <description>We copy the below top-fake-news-lists from opindia.com, a news analysis site - just in case that website goes away in the future.
General notable fakes  Breast tax in kerala. OP18  2019  1. The Wire uses 2015 survey and laces it with lies to say mental health issues on the rise in Kashmir post abrogation of Article 370  The report resorts to a classic propaganda method. It tries to add useless information in order to obfuscate from what the headline claims, that is, mental health deteriorating after the abrogation of Article 370.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wikipedia</title>
      <link>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/rags/wikipedia/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/rags/wikipedia/</guid>
      <description>Skewed control  &amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s interesting to note that there are many Bengali and Malayali senior editors on Wikipedia who have been editing Wikipedia pages for years. They&amp;rsquo;re staunch Leftists and their job is ensure that Wikipedia doesn&amp;rsquo;t say nice things about non-left personalities and media.&amp;rdquo; TW20 &amp;ldquo;A gang of about 50 Indian editors are on top of a chain of editors and they have complete control over Wikipedia. The top 50 editors are mostly from IT companies with much free time on their hands and they are on Wiki the whole day.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
