<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Geopolitics on hindu-vichArAH हिन्दु-विचाराः</title>
    <link>https://hindutva.github.io/main/polity/geopolitics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Geopolitics on hindu-vichArAH हिन्दु-विचाराः</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://hindutva.github.io/main/polity/geopolitics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>China</title>
      <link>https://hindutva.github.io/main/polity/geopolitics/China/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hindutva.github.io/main/polity/geopolitics/China/</guid>
      <description>Current status  Territorial aggression by mainland China is being opposed by a good coalition of neighbors - India, Japan, Taiwan, Vietnam, Korea, Mongolia, Russia.  Recent history  &amp;ldquo;The Han civilization was largely demolished by the cunning mlechCha-s, followed by a stern cut from the samurai’s blade. However, the mlechCha-s in their conquest of Japan ended up giving the chIna-s a new leash of life. The chIna-s not being the type that easily passes up an opportunity took the chance to resurrect their power and display their belligerence ever since.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Europe</title>
      <link>https://hindutva.github.io/main/polity/geopolitics/europe/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hindutva.github.io/main/polity/geopolitics/europe/</guid>
      <description>unmAda competition  &amp;ldquo;the fourth +++(rudhironmAda v2)+++ strain will win and in turn it would likely face defeat at the hands of the more vigorous marūnmāda.&amp;rdquo; - MT  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rich vs Poor</title>
      <link>https://hindutva.github.io/main/polity/geopolitics/Echonomic_rich_vs_the_poor/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hindutva.github.io/main/polity/geopolitics/Echonomic_rich_vs_the_poor/</guid>
      <description>Rich countries use unfair trade practices etc.. to suck much more money out of poorer countries than they provide in &amp;ldquo;aid&amp;rdquo; - TheRulesVid1. Fact-sheet excerpts here:
  Richest 200 people have about $2.7 trillion, which is more than the poorest 3.5 billion people, who have only $2.2 trillion combined.
  Poor countries: rich countries wealth ratio has been increasing and now stands at about 1:80. From the United Nations Development Program’s 1999 Human Development Report.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Russia</title>
      <link>https://hindutva.github.io/main/polity/geopolitics/Russia/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hindutva.github.io/main/polity/geopolitics/Russia/</guid>
      <description> Alexander Dugin [YT15]  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>USA</title>
      <link>https://hindutva.github.io/main/polity/geopolitics/usa/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hindutva.github.io/main/polity/geopolitics/usa/</guid>
      <description>unmAda competition  &amp;ldquo;Given that the current +++(rudhironmAda v2)+++ strain is still an unmāda it will compete vigorously with other unmāda-s for its host. Since, none of these unmāda-s kill the host the battle is not going to lead to attenuation in anyway&amp;hellip; In any case we can say that already a covert war between two unmāda-s, like the crusade and the jihād, is under way among the maha-mleccha.&amp;rdquo; - MT &amp;ldquo;Finally, the second amendment of the mahāmleccha constitution and those who know how to make use of it will be the last line of defense for the pretonmāda.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>०६ टेर्रोरिस्त् स्तते ओफ़् फकिस्तन् \[२०१२\]</title>
      <link>https://hindutva.github.io/main/polity/geopolitics/pakistAn/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hindutva.github.io/main/polity/geopolitics/pakistAn/</guid>
      <description>Pakistan&amp;rsquo;s problem with India (especially kashmir) is not one arising over the need for greater security (or neutralizing a threat) - but is ideological (Christine Fair video says: &amp;ldquo;a greedy state&amp;rdquo;). US strategy has been to attempt to put Pakistan at ease (via-a-vis India) by providing it with more weapons and aids - this has failed.
Pakistan&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;civil&amp;rdquo; society has roughly the same ideological preferences as the military. Its youth continue to be conservative.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
