<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Atheism on hindu-vichArAH हिन्दु-विचाराः</title>
    <link>https://hindutva.github.io/main/rivals/abe-disease/0-theism/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Atheism on hindu-vichArAH हिन्दु-विचाराः</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://hindutva.github.io/main/rivals/abe-disease/0-theism/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Anti-brAhmaNa</title>
      <link>https://hindutva.github.io/main/rivals/abe-disease/0-theism/anti-brAhmaNa/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hindutva.github.io/main/rivals/abe-disease/0-theism/anti-brAhmaNa/</guid>
      <description>Protestant background &amp;ldquo;If there were differences between Orientalists and Anglicists in this regard, they were very shallow. Anglicists found Indian culture and society intrinsically corrupt from the very beginning. Orientalists, however, saw India&amp;rsquo;s culture as being based on sound principles which steadily degenerated. But the cause of corruption, however, was in both cases the same, ie, &amp;lsquo;brahmanism&amp;rsquo;.&amp;rdquo; &amp;hellip; (See this page further.)
&amp;ldquo;If this suggestion is convincing, the prevalence of Europe&amp;rsquo;s conceptualisation in the modern Indian intellectual&amp;rsquo;s reflection on his own society is nothing but remarkable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Econo-theism</title>
      <link>https://hindutva.github.io/main/rivals/abe-disease/0-theism/artha-sAdhaka/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hindutva.github.io/main/rivals/abe-disease/0-theism/artha-sAdhaka/</guid>
      <description>Relation to local systems  &amp;ldquo;the world has come a long way from the sārthavāha-s of yore who even when wide-ranging did not disrupt the local systems. For instance, in say the Marahaṭṭā country, where we formerly lived, there was the system of the bārā balutedāra-s which has perhaps lasted in some form from the pre-Āryan days of the Harappan civilization. This system comprised of 12 jāti-s who offered essential services for a village.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oppressive system fetish</title>
      <link>https://hindutva.github.io/main/rivals/abe-disease/0-theism/rudhironmAda/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hindutva.github.io/main/rivals/abe-disease/0-theism/rudhironmAda/</guid>
      <description>Traits  For traits common with other Abe 0-theist maturations, see main page.  Change in perception of reality  Focus on &amp;ldquo;grievance studies&amp;rdquo;. See J Lindsay 20. They seek to warp the perception of reality in terms of oppressors and oppressed. Rooted in marxist concept of &amp;ldquo;conflict theory&amp;rdquo; of fundamental conflict between classes. Could be bourgeoisie vs proletariat or white vs black lives, male patriarchy vs women, hetero-normative straight culture vs sexual minorities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Secularism</title>
      <link>https://hindutva.github.io/main/rivals/abe-disease/0-theism/secularism/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hindutva.github.io/main/rivals/abe-disease/0-theism/secularism/</guid>
      <description>Intro  Secularist argument: &amp;ldquo;If your religious faith requires you to enforce its tenets on those who are not members of your faith-community, then your religion is incompatible with a free society and society has a right to defend itself against such encroachment.&amp;rdquo; Secularism, being in some sense &amp;ldquo;softer&amp;rdquo; in appearance to harder anti-theism and Abrahamisms, is insidious and dangerous from the heathen perspective. Hence it merits a separate page. Alternative phrases that helps us understand secularism better  sickularism (via Ambreesh) - post-christian christianism.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>