<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Indo-aryan on hindu-vichArAH हिन्दु-विचाराः</title>
    <link>https://hindutva.github.io/paganology/Aryan/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Indo-aryan on hindu-vichArAH हिन्दु-विचाराः</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://hindutva.github.io/paganology/Aryan/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>02 Aryan invasion</title>
      <link>https://hindutva.github.io/paganology/Aryan/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/Arya-invasion/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hindutva.github.io/paganology/Aryan/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/Arya-invasion/</guid>
      <description>yAmnAya corded-ware baltic-fatyanovo abashevo sintashta andronovo nordquvist 2020     narasimhan19-admixture     yAmnAya corded-ware farmer mixture 18   The mAnasatarangiNIkAra and others have spoken on this here: MT1803, N201803, 20151212 (mindmup map, img, base file here), RK16, H17,20151219, 2015BX, 201209. Also see notes in the &amp;ldquo;current genetics section&amp;rdquo; below.
The (more credible) AIT narrative of Bronze age events.
Old home Indo-Aryans initially resided in the area around/ beyond the Black Sea, and were familiar with cold and long dawns (as evidenced by some parts of the Vedic texts - long ashvina-shastra to be recited at dawn).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>03 Arya consolidation</title>
      <link>https://hindutva.github.io/paganology/Aryan/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/Arya-consolidation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hindutva.github.io/paganology/Aryan/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/Arya-consolidation/</guid>
      <description>Spread within India  From baudhAyana and manu, it is clear that kuru-pAnchAla realm was where major brAhmaNa vedic consolidation happened. Gradually, this culture and its carriers (mainly in the form of brAhmaNa-s) spread elsewhere in India and beyond. {GA_17}  baudhAyana-dharma-sUtra implies that vaidika karma-s can only be conducted in the &amp;ldquo;madhya-desha&amp;rdquo;, not even in kalinga, vanga, AraTTa, gAndhAra etc.. - going where expiation is required [TW]. Yet, we observe baudhAyana-s and vaidika-s in kerala and TN.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Final composition</title>
      <link>https://hindutva.github.io/paganology/Aryan/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/varNa-composition/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hindutva.github.io/paganology/Aryan/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/varNa-composition/</guid>
      <description>kShatriya-s  &amp;ldquo;The brAhmaNas (brahmins) and the kShatriyas are in essense the descendents of the aristocracy or elite families of the invading Aryans. Overtime the kShatriya fold adopted other Indo-Aryan tribes outside of the pa~nchajana-ikShvAku orthodoxy, and various “honorary” kShatriyas of diverse ethnic backgrounds. These newcomers displaced or supplemented the original kShatriyas to a significant degree.&amp;rdquo; [MT1]  brAhmaNa-s  &amp;ldquo;However, in the case of the brahmin the displacement was less significant, though there was a noticeable ethnic diversification through the process of anuloma marriage and the 7 generation rule of ascent to brahmin-hood.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reactions to AIT</title>
      <link>https://hindutva.github.io/paganology/Aryan/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/AIT-reactions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hindutva.github.io/paganology/Aryan/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/AIT-reactions/</guid>
      <description>Embracing AIT  In 1898 Tilak wrote &amp;ldquo;The Arctic Home in the Vedas&amp;rdquo;. This work propounded the theory that the North Pole was the original home of the Aryans in the pre-glacial period, who migrated to the Northern parts of Europe, Asia and eventually India by about 3000 BCE. Savarkar wrote a booklet named &amp;ldquo;Essentials Of Hindutva&amp;rdquo; in 1923 - a foundational document in the history of the movement. In that pamphlet, he implicitly accepts the Aryan Invasion theory by talking of Aryans as a distinct race.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>